Your summer camp starts today?
Where are you going again?
The Geological Museum and JAXA!
Endou-sensei suggested it.
Wow, sounds nice!
Have enough fun for me, too.
Oh, and sneak pictures of
everyone's sleeping faces!
Look, a rocket!
That's the Expo Center's life-size model.
Do you know this area well?
Kinda, yeah.
I lived here in my high school days.
Hey, what's that?
That car's like a robot!
Hey, keep it down! You made me miss our turn!
Geological
Museum
04. Exciting! Summer Camp!
We're here!
You're restless for once.
I'm not acting any different.
I see rock samples in books all the time, after all.
Senpai, Senpai, look at this! It's amazing!
What is it?
A molted praying mantis shell!
Oh, how cute!
Ow, ow!
Darn you people!
What did I do?!
Good grief.
Earth Sciences Club
Summer Camp
Botanical
Garden
Geological
Museum
JAXA
Space Center
Endou-sensei has a nice proposal
for our summer camp.
Botanical
Garden
Want to go to my grandma's place?
Wow, those faces...
Grandma's Place
Geological
Museum
Geopark
No, what I mean is,
why don't we stay at her place to save money
and go visit places nearby?
Places nearby?
Earth Sciences Club
Summer Camp
JAXA
Space Center
Geological
Museum
Geopark
Botanical
Garden
There's the JAXA Space Center,
the Geological Museum, Geopark, and...
I guess that settles it?
Fascinating
Minerals
Wow, there are so many stones!
Minerals and fossils...
They're quite something, aren't they, Sakura-ch—
This is the actual stone used in reference books!
Ino-cha—
Sakura-senpai is enjoying herself
so much, I'm having fun, too!
Let's back away slowly…
Yeah...
Did you find something interesting?
This one.
Look at that! There's sparkly golden dice
coming out of the rock!
Yamanashi Pref. Stone (Mineral)
This one's heart-shaped.
I wonder how they end up in such pretty shapes.
Hmm...
Hmm?
It's Yamanashi's prefectural stone?
Yamanashi Pref. Stone (Mineral)
Each region has a stone that represents it.
That's recognized as its prefectural stone.
Kyoto Pref. Stone (Mineral)
This one's my favorite!
Cherry Blossom Stone?
Yes!
It's Kyoto's stone, and it's a national treasure.
It really does look like a cherry blossom!
It's so cute and rare! It really is
a prized flower beyond reach!
It's just like Sakura-senpai, and I love it!
Huh?
What?
The geology group's excitement is incredible.
What are you looking at, Sensei?
Ah, lots and lots of gemstones!
I wonder how much all of these
are worth together...
Money...
Monroe-senpai, what's on display there?
It looks delicious!
Her appetite...
E-Everyone has their own way of enjoying things.
Ah!
This is incredible.
I don't think we can see everything in one day!
I wish we could stay here forever.
Mira, did you bring the stone?
Oh, yeah, I did.
What stone?
During our riverside barbecue,
Mira picked up a stone
and I think it might be a fossil.
I thought I'd have them examine it here.
I tripped and the stone split open.
What is that?! That's terrifying!
Fossil One...
Mira, you looked into it yourself, didn't you?
I wasn't sure if it was a fossil or not,
so I decided to do some research first.
Fun With Fossils
Really?
This book is pretty easy to understand!
Fun with Fossils
Author, Illustrator: Tanaka Hanako
Editor: Yamada Tarou
Oh, it is!
My, that looks fun to read.
Fun with Fossils
Author, Illustrator: Tanaka Hanako
Editor: Yamada Tarou
A picture book...
Let's see, so after a plant or animal dies,
it has to get buried in mud or sand quickly.
If it doesn't, it gets eaten
by other animals or rots away.
Uh-huh.
Then, it gets pressed under the weight of the mud
and minerals seep into it.
Thousands of years later, it's a fossil.
In recent experiments, they've discovered fossils that can form in a few weeks.
You mean... if you buried me right now,
Fossilized
Mira
I could be a fossil for this year's cultural festival!
That'd be a serious crime.
I'm surprised, though.
I can't believe we found a fossil in a river stone.
They're not that rare, actually.
There's a chance of finding one
wherever there's sedimentary rock.
Wow! Did you find all of these, Sakura-chan?
I-I bought all but this one
and this one from a science museum.
Sakura-senpai's too honest!
Anyway, it could be a fossil
that surfaced after thousands of years,
so I want to find out what it might be.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Come on, it's time!
Hmm...
I found the stone by the river.
What section of the river did you pick it up from?
Uh, it was around here.
Which means...
Um, is this a fossil of a leaf
from thousands of years ago?
Hey, quiet down.
It's possible that large black spot
might not be a fossil.
Huh?
What?! But Sakura-senpai
was so confident when she said—
I said be quiet!
Have you ever heard of dendrite?
Pseudofossil
Dendrite?
Yes, it's named for its tree-like formations.
Pseudofossil
It forms when manganese flows between rocks,
producing this plant-like structure.
It's easy to mistake it for a fossil,
so they're often called pseudofossils.
A fake fossil...
Oh, but wait, look here.
Spicules
Fish Scale
This shiny spot, about three millimeters wide.
This is from a fish scale, I think.
Also, they're tiny and hard to see,
but can you see the tiny lines just past the label?
Let's take a look with this.
I see them!
Those are likely the spicules of sea sponges.
It's probably the skeletal structure of a sea
creature from the end of the Precambrian Era.
It's very small, but it's a real fossil.
A fossil!
A fossil! A fossil!
Here you go. This explains the geological map
of the area where you found the stone.
Thank you!
The names and history of the strata...
Even the commonly found fossils
are described in here.
You can view those records online, too.
Do you want to see how?
Yes, please!
The geology group fell asleep.
There was a lot for them to take in, after all.
Sakura-chan was especially excited today.
Yeah, just like a kid.
She was even cuter than usual.
Sakura-senpai!
She's not waking up at all.
You're not a kid, so please use your legs!
Oh, it's Yuki! And her students!
Welcome.
It must have been a long trip.
I'm back.
Thank you for having us.
Mira, her grandfather's hat...
Huh? JAXA?
Don't tell me her grandfather works there!
Not a problem.
But hold on. The logo looks a little off.
It's JA's!
The farmers' cooperative!
He's a farmer that loves space.
Please go easy on him.
Info wanted!
Searching for asteroids.
Hello!
Info wanted!
Searching for asteroids.
We're Hoshizaki High School's
earth sciences club!
What's that?
W-We're searching for an asteroid.
It's a plan they came up with
before our summer camp.
We're Hoshizaki High School's earth sciences club!
Doing that at the space center
just makes it look like they're fooling around.
Oh, but someone's talking to them.
Searching for asteroids.
We got candy!
Info wanted!
Searching for asteroids.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
So, to take the observation tour,
we need to meet up at...
PHONE
Grandpa
Missed Call
PHONE
Grandpa
Missed Call
PHONE
Grandpa
Missed Call
PHONE
Grandpa
Missed Call
PHONE
Grandpa
Missed Call
Press home to unlock
Grandpa...
Your grandfather looked like
he really wanted to come.
Are you sure we shouldn't have brought him along?
Huh?
Oh, no, it's fine.
This is your summer camp, after all.
A rocket!
What you saw yesterday was just a model,
but this is a real rocket, even on the inside.
A real one?!
I want to touch it!
Hey, Monroe, your astronomy group
is getting carried away.
As our president, you need to watch... them...
I can't reach it!
Space is so far away!
They all get along so well.
Yeah.
This is incredible, Ao!
It's a space center!
Maybe we'll find a hint
on discovering our asteroid!
Yeah.
Are you two interested in asteroids?
Come on, Sensei! We told you about it
the day we joined this club!
Huh? Did you?
Senpai, let's take a photo to mark the moment!
I see.
Thank you all for participating
in the observation tour.
Let's get started by watching this video.
This is the place closest to space in all of Japan.
Welcome to the space center.
Here we'll introduce JAXA's various projects.
Space is incredible! Mankind is incredible!
Huh? Mira-chan?
I don't think this video is supposed to make you cry.
Getting older sucks.
Are we the minority here?
Now I'll show you all
to the astronaut training wing.
Normally, only staff are allowed into this area,
Monroe-senpai's looking more serious than usual.
so please wear the passes
I gave you somewhere visible.
Well, I'm sure she has a lot of thoughts
running through her mind.
She's always wanted to come here.
She has?
These space suits weigh roughly 120 kilograms.
They include life support, oxygen, and batteries.
As well, when they're working outside the ship…
On the other side of this window
is the closed-environment training facility.
Previous exams narrowed
our 963 applicants down to ten,
who are taking their tests in here.
Excuse me, what does it take
to become an astronaut?
Well, first, you have to be healthy,
and also proficient in English.
And above all else, you need to be cooperative.
That's said to be the most important part.
Thank you very much.
No problem.
Over here, we place astronauts
in low-pressure environments to measure
You heard her.
Sakura-chan.
Thank you very much.
how low oxygen supplies will affect their bodies
and conduct other training regimes.
You'll need to work more on your pronunciation.
We should try asking her about asteroids, too!
Asteroids?
Yes!
We were hoping for a hint on how to discover one.
I'm just a tour guide, so I don't know
very much about that...
but one of the exhibit hall's
commentators might be able to help.
Searching for asteroids.
Oh, I see.
I'm sorry.
No worries. Thank you for the advice.
Searching for asteroids.
All right! The enemy waits in the exhibit hall!
Let's go, Ao!
Yeah!
It's a manmade satellite!
It's an exhibit about the Hayabusa.
I'm sure someone here can help...
H-Hi, excuse me!
You want to discover an asteroid?
D-Do you have any hints for us?
Any hints, eh?
Or do you know anyone who might be
an expert in that field?
Well, this center is focused
on space development,
so while we have some exhibits
on the discovery of asteroids,
we don't know much about
discovering new astronomical objects.
Though there may be a specialist in one of our other centers elsewhere in the country.
Is that so?
Thank you.
Not at all.
Thank you very much!
I couldn't find any clues.
Ao...
Me, neither. But I learned a lot today,
and I also realized a few things.
For example,
if we try each of the centers throughout Japan,
we'll eventually meet an expert on it!
Searching for asteroids.
You're too optimistic.
Sakura-chan, thanks for your help.
Honestly, I couldn't just watch you girls...
And you should be helping, too!
Yay!
Where's your cooperation?!
Sensei, we're done looking around!
Oh, nice.
Look, space meals!
They sell all different kinds!
A replica space suit!
Sensei, what did you buy?
I should be asking you!
Well then, we should head back now.
Wait, where's Monroe?
She went to use the restroom.
You sure took your time.
What's that look for?
Space is so far away!
Huh?
Oh hi, welcome back!
Everything's ready for the barbecue.
Wow! It's like a festival!
I had a lot of free time, so I put some effort into it.
Oh, jeez...
I'm sorry I didn't bring you with us, okay?
You can have this as an apology.
Y-Yuki!
I guess tonight's a full moon, isn't it?
Yeah, it is. That makes it harder to see the stars.
Nights like that are good
for viewing the moon, though.
Shall I break out the telescope, then?
Can you students help me with that?
Sure!
Hey, it has an equatorial mount!
It has different parts than the one our club uses.
The mount on ours is an alt-azimuth mount that moves the telescope vertically and horizontally.
This one uses an equatorial mount
that moves in time with the earth's rotation.
Once you move the handle on an equatorial mount,
it'll keep following that star forever.
It's so much easier!
Yes!
I want to see, too!
I thought the moon was bumpier than that.
It's surprisingly flat.
Oh, that's because the sun's light
reflects head-on during the full moon,
so it's harder to see the bumps from the craters.
By the way, the bright part
with lots of craters is mostly anorthosite,
and the dark parts are made of basalt.
Wow, really?
Ah, she got that off her chest.
You studied up on it, didn't you?
You should all study up on rocks a bit more!
You're taking it out on us?!
Hey, we have watermelon!
Watermelon?!
Oh, yes. Here's what you asked us to look for, Yuki.
Oh, you found it? Thanks.
An old flyer?
For high schoolers... An astronomical
object discovery program?
Huh?
Shining Star
Challenge
Applic
ations
Now
Open
What? What is this?!
It's the Shining Star Challenge program
held at the observatory during summer break.
I participated in it myself back in the day.
I couldn't find anything, though.
Wh-Wh-
Why would you keep such
incredible information a secret?!
Well I mean, I wasn't aware about your dream.
Really? But when we first joined the club...
Sorry. I was sleeping in the next room over.
You slept through it...
Oh.
The deadline for entering this year
has already passed.
New Astronomical Object Discovery
Program for High Schoolers
Shining Star Challenge
Applications for this event are closed.
Add to list
If only we had known about this sooner!
It's held on Ishigaki Island.
You're mad, aren't you?!
Okinawa? That sounds great!
Ishigaki Island...
Okinawa...
Blue seas...
Mira?
The Shining Star Challenge.
It's open to all high schoolers in the nation.
Seven participants are selected
based on their submitted assignment.
It's hard to get in, and there's no guarantee
that we'll discover one, huh?
But I still feel, even just a bit,
like we're a step or two closer to our goal.
Yeah.
This might be a huge leap forward for us.
Yeah!
This brings back memories.
Your eyes sparkled just like theirs
when you came home from Ishigaki Island.
Touring JAXA, having a barbecue,
viewing the stars...
and ending with fireworks.
We've been going all-out.
I never expected Endou-sensei to be someone
who hunted for new asteroids, though.
I didn't know that, either.
My heart's been racing all day long.
I guess this means everyone in the astronomy
group has gotten closer to their goals.
Everyone?
I...
...want to become an astronaut.
An astronaut?
Really?
Yeah.
So that's why you were acting so serious today.
It's such a big dream, it's kinda embarrassing.
You shouldn't call it embarrassing.
Not if you're serious about pursuing it.
I still haven't found any solid goal
to pursue, so if you ask me,
you're all amazing for having one.
You shouldn't hold back in pursuing your dreams.
Sakura-chan, thank you.
Hmph.
Wait, that means...
You're not mad at us?
Huh? This is me encouraging you.
I-It was hard to tell...
Don't hold back on your dreams...
I think I might have figured out
what I want to do.
The truth is, there's somewhere I'd like to go, too!
This is the headquarters of map-making,
the Geospatial Informational Authority of Japan!
I didn't know Inose was into this field.
I know this is a change of plans.
Are you all okay with this?
I don't mind at all.
Besides...
I don't think anyone can complain
when they see that look on her face.
Tsukuba VLBI Antenna (1998–2016)
No wonder it felt a little lonesome.
What's the matter, Sensei?
Hmm? Oh, there used to be this huge
parabolic antenna around there.
Sensei!
We found the antenna!
I think I've gone from
feeling nostalgic to feeling happy.
We discovered new sides of
our clubmates at this summer camp.
We learned so much during our tours, too,
and it feels like the world
has opened up for everyone.
Before, our goal of
discovering an asteroid felt vague...
But I'm sure there's a star out there
just like the tiny fossil
I discovered by the riverside.
It's somewhere out there in this universe.
Everyone's Summer Break
Next time: "Everyone's Summer Break."