Suzu-chan's been busy helping
her family during summer break,
but at her suggestion,
we're all here at the beach!
It's the beach!
Mira, what are you doing?
Collecting rocks.
It seems she's been enjoying the
field of geology lately, as well.
She totally acts like a
geology club member now.
What's the matter, Ino-senpai?
Just thinking you two both
look lovely and mature.
I should have gone with
a swimsuit like that, too.
Would you like to wear a pareo?
So cute! Nice! So nice!
You look good it in, Senpai!
05.     Everyone's Summer Break
I wish Sakura-senpai and Monroe-senpai
could have joined us, too.
Summer classes sound rough.
Yeah!
Mira, don't move without warning.
Looks like you two have grown
quite close to each other.
Especially you, Ao.
Yeah, I can talk to her like normal now.
We went to a hot spring together,
and we had a sleepover, too!
The beach is so fun!
It is.
Let's swim more!
Now that I think about it,
Yeah!
I don't think there's ever been any
girl who was closer to Mira than me.
Could this be...
what people call "jealousy"?!
I'm hungry!
Why don't we have lunch now?
Lunch!
Ao, let's have a match!
Huh?
A best-of-three match over
who's Mira's best friend!
Huh?!
Hey, Mira...
Beach House
Sea Gravel
Round one!
Preparing Mira's favorite food!
How did this happen?
I know Mira loves strawberries.
If I remember right, she likes pork cutlets.
And... showdown!
I love them both!
It's hard to compare
different genres of food.
Round two!
A competition to see who
can touch Mira first!
Ino-senpai, please start us off!
Okay!
Though, before we start,
make sure you both keep
a look out for rip tides.
Beware of Rip Tides!
Don't go in the ocean
when the waves are rough.
Rip tides?
Strong currents that flow
from the shore out to sea.
If you get pulled into that current,
you'll drift farther and farther
out to sea, so be very careful.
Huh?
Mira!
Sorry about that.
You girls just weren't coming,
so I started swimming.
I'm so glad you weren't drifting away.
That was no time to be
worrying about our match.
So, getting back to business,
I think we should have Ino-senpai
decide the final match. It's only fair.
Huh?
We're still doing this?
Okay, why don't we have everyone ride that?
Wow, that looks fun!
Huh?
There are a few waves out here,
so the boat might rock.
Okay!
Suzu-chan, your hair!
Oh, sorry!
She let go?!
I'm falling!
Mira!
Suzu-san!
That scared me!
Both of you started falling together.
I was just trying to rescue you, Mira.
I was trying to rescue Suzu-san.
You both ignored the match.
You're so kind.
If you can show that much
concern for each other,
what's wrong with all three
of you being best friends?
All three?
I get it.
Did Senpai propose the boat for our
match because she saw this coming?
Still, this is incredible!
You can see the strata so clearly!
I wish could show this to Sakura-senpai, too!
I guess not.
Ino-senpai's asleep.
She's worn out from all the fun.
Ao...
I'm sorry for getting you
all wound up in my jealousy.
Huh? Oh, you were feeling jealous?
Now I get it.
I'm sorry, too.
I often don't notice how others are feeling.
I see.
I'll have to tell you what I'm thinking
more clearly from now on, then.
Well, to put it out there,
I hope we can get along in many
ways as new best friends.
Oh, it's from Monroe-senpai.
Huh?! Why's she in a swimsuit?!
And Sakura-senpai, too?!
She says, "We finished our summer classes,
so now we're relaxing at the school pool."
Please give me those photos,
as your best friend!
What is your definition of "best friend"?
Oh, Jupiter.
Huh? You can see it?
Oh, you can!
Wow. You can tell which planet it is at a glance.
Yeah, generally, due to its color and brightness.
I've only learned about the stars in class,
but maybe I should make it
a point to learn more.
Huh? What?
Monthly Star Navi
That's probably her way of showing
affection, so you should accept it.
Oh, sure.
With that, Suzu-chan's very
fulfilling day came to an end.
It wasn't much longer until the
last night of summer break.
Oh, Sakura-senpai.
I'm going to a mineral show tomorrow.
I'll send where to meet up later.
Please let me know if you can make it.
Mineral show?
I wonder what that is. I'll totally go.
I'm sorry, I have other plans already.
What a shame. I have plans that day, too.
I'm sorry, I do, too.
Huh? No one else can come?
Which means... I'll be alone with Sakura-senpai?
Good morning!
Good morning. You're early.
Yeah, um, I got a little nervous when
I realized it's just the two of us.
Since you're so serious about things.
I figured you were likely
to get mad if I was late,
and you're really scary
when you're mad, Senpai.
What a coincidence.
I'm pretty nervous myself.
Ow, ow, ow!
Are you really nervous?!
There are so many people.
Did you notice a lot of them are women?
They're also selling power stones
and materials for accessories.
I see.
Hey, are you listening to me?
Power stone to calm a scary person
Why are you peeking at my phone?!
Ow.
What are you looking for here, Senpai?
I haven't settled on anything
specific, actually.
I'm mostly here for a break from my studies.
It's fun enough just walking
around and looking.
Wow, so you're window shopping for stones!
Oh! It's the chisel set
I've been looking for!
I'll take this, please! And this!
Oh, and give me this too, please!
How pretty.
Hi.
Which power stone do you want?
Uh, um...
Excuse me.
Could you make this a little cheaper?
Okay. Just a moment, please.
Sure!
You're so reliable.
I'm not leaving your side at all today!
Jeez, you're just sweet-talking me.
Those have rubber bands around them.
Yeah, those are geodes.
It's split!
The inside is made up of crystallized minerals.
If I remember right, there's a demo corner
where you can split geodes yourself.
Wow, a rock splitting demo!
It's the perfect chance to
show off your iron fist!
That compliment's actually quite rude.
This is fun. There are stones
as far as the eye can see!
Minerals,
fossils,
and meteors...
Huh? Meteors?
Senpai, Senpai! They're selling meteors!
You're too loud.
If you found one you like, why not buy it?
Right!
Maybe I'll get one as a souvenir for Ao.
You bought a lot, huh?
Yeah. It was so interesting,
I couldn't help it.
This is that geode we saw before,
and the one that looks like
it has two layers is calcite.
There's a bismuth crystal
with mysterious coloring,
and a pretty banded stone!
The banded stones you find
all have strange patterns.
What did you buy, Senpai?
Want to see? You want to see?!
Uh, never mind.
Today was a really great breather.
I interacted with lots of sparkly stones,
and enjoyed some fluffy pancakes...
Now you can really study
hard when you get home!
You're getting depressed!
Entrance exams are tough, aren't they?
It's more like...
I just can't get myself into it.
I know I mentioned it during summer camp,
but I don't have any clear goals.
Your dream is to discover a star, right?
Yes! An asteroid, technically. Not a star.
If you do manage to find one,
what will you do after that?
After that?
When you're an adult.
Do you have a career or an
occupation you're aiming for?
When you put it like that...
I have no idea.
I really do envy you.
Sorry for bringing up a weird topic.
Kind of ruined the break, huh?
Let's get another cake.
Doesn't it look like strata?
It does.
You're starting to be more
like us geology girls.
Let's excavate!
This walnut fossil is delicious!
Sorry for taking up your entire day.
No, I had fun!
Thank you so much!
Wh-What's this?
To thank you for inviting me out today.
I hope we can bring everyone
else with us next time.
Well, my house is this way.
Huh?
Y-Yeah, see you later.
I forgot to thank her for
coming with me, didn't I?
Silicate Mineral
Mohs Hardness 8
Topaz.
The stone that helps you find
the path you should take, huh?
What a sophisticated thing to do.
Thank you for today.
I really had a lot of fun.
No, it doesn't seem right
to say it to her like that.
I was happy you were there to listen to me.
I'll do my best with my studies.
Uh, who would say that?
Oh, Sakura-senpai.
Thank you for today.
I'll study hard, so make sure
to give it your best, too!
Growr!
Senpai?
What I Want to Be
Sensei! I want to be a train driver!
I want to be a cake baker!
An astronaut!
I want to be a train driver, too.
That's lovely, everyone.
What about you, Mikage-chan?
Huh?
What do you want to be in the future?
I...
Morning!
Oh, morning!
Sakura-senpai, good morning.
Oh, morning.
Do we have a meeting today?
Huh?
Oh, yes. After school.
Right.
The cultural festival's coming up soon,
so we need to start making
decisions on things.
Right.
It's still so hot.
L-Look.
Wh-What?
Ibe-chan?!
Eve!
I told you to call me Eve, didn't I?!
She's one of my friends from class.
Friends?
Oh, it's Manaka-san!
Yoohoo!
Usami-san.
Someone you know?
A classmate.
Sorry, our Eve-senpai is such a pain.
Reconnaissance?
That's right!
We're a secret squad within the
newspaper club that's taking
covert action to crush the
earth sciences club's newsletter!
This is my first time seeing covert action!
Our Senpai is a little off,
but the girls of the earth sciences
club are pretty spacey too, huh?
You said you're going to crush our newsletter?
Could you tell us what you mean by that?
I can't share too many details,
but our newspaper's not selling.
It must be because the earth sciences
club's newsletter is right beside it,
and yours is interesting and full of content!
I think we're being praised and
reprimanded at the same time.
You're such an honest girl.
So you're trying to stop the production
of the earth sciences club's newsletter?
Yeah!
I was just looking for any scandals
that we could use as blackmail!
You spilled everything
in barely a few minutes.
You're dumber than Mira.
Huh?
Did you find any scandals?
I tried spying on your club
room from several angles,
and I found nothing!
I was just looking for any scandals
that we could use as blackmail!
Oh, my, what a shame.
Especially since you just shared something
we can blackmail the newspaper club with.
Huh?! When did you...
You can do whatever you want to me!
Well, it's not like you're causing any
harm by peeking into the club room.
I'm so sorry. She just loves
making everything dramatic.
I know! Why don't you help us think
of an exhibit for the cultural festival?
An exhibit for...
...the cultural festival?
I know! I want to create a
model of our solar system!
Uh-huh!
That sounds nice.
Last year, the geology club made a display
board showing off their research, right?
Yes.
Surprisingly, few people actually read it.
I guess we need some kind of
exhibit that draws attention.
Something both kids and adults can enjoy.
I know! Why don't we
cosplay again this year?!
Rejected.
An exhibit that draws attention, huh?
You need something huge!
Could you bring in any giant
rocks from the mountains?
Oh! You'll need an explosion too, then!
"Blast" would be the correct term.
I shouldn't have said anything.
Sakura-senpai, do you think
we could bring in some strata?
You mean a surface peel specimen?
I've never made one before,
and I'm not sure we have a rocky
outcropping we could use as a specimen.
How about a boring survey of the campus, then?
Hmph!
I get it, but it's not "bowling."
You mean "boring" as in drilling holes, right?
Boring Survey
Pop
Right. You drive a pipe into the
ground and bore out a sample.
So if you can add an explosion
and a huge rock to that...
Yes, Eve-chan-senpai. You're embarrassing yourself,
so we should be getting back now.
Boring does sound fun, though.
Let's give it some thought.
Excuse me.
Inose, are you here scouting
us out this time?!
No, it's not about that.
I'm actually here because something
strange happened this morning.
Oh, an incident?!
Over summer break, someone named the koi.
Feynman              Dirac                Fermi            Cockcroft
Well, I guess that could
make for a filler article.
I'm surprised you noticed
these tiny signs, though.
Because I've been watching
them since my first year here.
I guess some people might
find this interesting.
That reminds me.
You've changed a bit, haven't you?
Your bangs are a bit shorter than
they were in the first semester.
I can tell because I was always watching.
Senpai, your heart just
skipped a beat, didn't it?
Sh-Shut up!
As if! That means nothing to me!
Yes, yes.
Boring Survey
Planetary Model Display
Model Explanation Board
Fossil Appraisal
Fusulinid Stone
Polishing Experience
I kind of expected it,
but really trying to conduct a boring survey
would be costly in both money and labor.
It says, "The harvested boring cores
are kept under school custody."
Staff Room
Looks like the school only has paper records.
I see.
This is cute. It's like masking tape.
Soil Boring Log
Yeah, this is how you illustrate
the results of a boring survey.
Araya-sensei, do we have agar?
We do.
That's so cool!
It's a mock boring survey.
I know!
Why don't we serve this as a café?
Agar
Boring Agar
Strawberry
Milk
Banana
Coffee
Agar!!
A café?
We could make other sweets and drinks
with earth science themes.
A café where you can enjoy earth sciences
along with tea and sweets...
A geocafé!
That might be nice!
It's settled, then.
Ao! Let's come up with some ideas for
sweets and talk to Suzu-chan about them!
Yeah.
Then the geology group's exhibit
for the café will be...
Actually boring into the campus?
We can't do that. It's not realistic.
We can't ask other businesses to
help with the cultural festival.
Hey, Sakurai.
If you're interested in it,
why not just organize what data
and findings you can dig up?
But without the real thing, it won't
be a centerpiece for the exhibit,
and it'll just look haphazard.
And that's fine.
It'd be a waste to just decide it's
impossible and completely scrap it all, right?
At the very least, I want to learn what
you researched and what you thought of it.
I want to know, too.
Yeah.
And so our earth sciences club begins
preparing for the cultural festival!
06.
Hoshizaki Festival!
Next time, "Hoshizaki Festival!"