KiraKira Special Issue!
The theme for Episode 2 is:
Sedimentary rock
Igneous rock
Metamorphic rock
Rocks formed by the deposition and subsequent cementation of dirt, sand, and organism remains.
Rocks formed by the cooling and solidification of magma.
Rocks that have been transformed under intense heat and pressure.
All About Rocks
All About Rocks.
Listen up! Rocks are classified
into three main types.
They're further classified by their constituent elements.
Sedimentary
Igneous
Metamorphic
Clastic
Pyroclastic
Organic sedimentary
Chemical sedimentary
Conglomerate
Sandstone
Mudstone
Tuff
Limestone
Chert
Halite
Volcanic
Plutonic
Basalt
Andesite
Rhyolite
Gabbro
Diorite
Granite
Contact metamorphic
Regional metamorphic
Hornfels
Marble
Schist
Gneiss
My head’s spinning from all the details.
Did you know? The banded stone Mira picked up at the river banks is a piece of mudstone!
The stripe was formed by dissolved
quartz that seeped into the rock.
You’re amazing, Senpai!
Oh, hey! Do you think you could
take a look at the other rocks I picked up?
Wha—?! Why’d you break them?
You can’t inspect them properly without
looking at their fresh insides, now can you?
My banded stone!
Cast
Konohata Mira
Takayanagi Tomoyo
Sakurai Mikage
Toyama Nao
Script
Sakai Fumiyo
Animation
Chito
Director
Hiramaki Daisuke
Background
Studio Naya
Photography
Kudo Yasushi
Resources Provision
Toshin Books
THE END
written and produced
Hoshizaki High School Earth Sciences Club
© Quro-Houbunsha / Hoshizaki High School Earth Sciences Club