utsumuita saki ni mo
I look at the ground in front of me
miageteru saki ni mo
I look at the sky that all can see
kitto mirai wa matteiru yo
The future's ahead of us. It waits for us, you know
dakara aruite yukou
So let's keep moving forward and go!
suki na koto ni wa itsudatte
Pursuing things I love, I want that for all time
enryo sezu ni ikitai na
I'd like to live my life without holding back
terekakushi mo mayoi mo sutetara
Toss my doubts and my fears. My unease, throw it all away
ato wa yuuki dake
In the end, my courage remains
donna kakudo kara mite mo
I look around me, up above, down below
sekai wa hirogatteru yo
The world is vast, so very vast, don't you know?
mita koto no nai mono
Looking for the things I've never seen
mitsukete yukitai na
Going to the spots I've never been
kagayaku ishi wo hiroiatsumete
The will to do all those things is what I want to have within
utsumuita saki ni mo
I look at the ground in front of me
miageteru saki ni mo
I look at the sky that all can see
kitto mirai wa matteiru yo
The future's ahead of us. It waits for us, you know
dakara aruite yukou
So let's keep moving forward and go!