KiraKira Special Issue!
For our commemorable first issue:
Mira
Cetus
A pulsating variable star. As the star expands and contracts over a period of approximately 332 days, its apparent magnitude fluctuates between 2.0 and 10.1.
Variable Star Mira
All about the variable star Mira.
Ao, you told me one time that
there's a star with the same name as me.
Yeah. Mira is a pulsating variable star.
Its magnitude can vary greatly over the course of a year.
Pulsating?
That's right. It gets colder and dimmer as it expands,
and it gets warmer and brighter as it contracts.
By expanding and contracting,
you mean like this?
Mira!
Cast
Konohata Mira: Takayanagi Tomoyo
Manaka Ao: Yamaguchi Megumi
Script: Yamada Yuka
Animation: Chito
Director: Hiramaki Daisuke
Background: Studio Naya
Photography: Kudo Yasushi
FIN
Produced and written by
Hoshizaki High School Earth Sciences Club
© Quro-Houbunsha / Hoshizaki High School Earth Sciences Club